

# MATTHEW CALLAHAN

Software Developer | Phoenix, Arizona

# **EDUCATION**



## **University of Wisconsin-Madison**

Bachelor of Science, Geographic Information Systems

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### CBRE | Phoenix, Arizona

Sr. Application Developer: September 2021 - Present

• Senior Application Developer with CBRE Location Intelligence, supporting GIS.

#### Theorem | Los Angeles, California

Engineering Manager: March 2021 - August 2021

- Lead a team of remote software engineers, overseeing the architecture, development, and delivery of custom software for clients.
- Managed nine direct reports, coaching and supporting each engineer's career growth, and evaluating their performance.
- Prioritized, delegated, and supervised all engineers' tasks and deliverables.
- Communicated and collaborated with product managers, designers, stakeholders, and clients to drive the project execution.

## Republic Services | Scottsdale, Arizona

Staff Engineer: May 2019 - March 2021

Senior Developer: December 2018 - May 2019

- Lead a team of developers and testers by prioritizing tasks, delegating duties, and guiding projects to successful and on-time delivery.
- Established and implemented a standard application architecture for greenfield development, allowing developers to rapidly begin coding and reducing the time needed to deliver a minimum viable product.
- Implemented unit test standards for the team and led effort to increase test coverage in all applications, reducing the number of production bugs.
- Authored coding conventions and style guide documents for developers and led successful effort to refactor applications to follow these guidelines.

#### Carvana | Tempe, Arizona

Software Engineer: January 2018 - December 2018

- Primary job function was back-end development to create and maintain the APIs and microservices which powered carvana.com using C#, .NET & .NET Core.
- Supported front end development to maintain and enhance a mobile responsive UI for vehicle inventory search engine (JavaScript ES6, React & Redux).
- Implemented A/B testing to help drive data analytics and deliver the best UX.

#### **CBRE | Phoenix, Arizona**

Application Developer: January 2011 – January 2018 GIS Technician: March 2008 – January 2011

• Developed web and desktop applications which provided mapping, site selection, and data analysis tools for real estate brokers and their clients using C#, .NET, WinForms, MapBasic, ArcGIS Pro .NET SDK, and Python.

## **ABOUT ME**

My name is Matthew Callahan, and I am a player-coach in the software world. I enjoy writing code as well as leading my team and mentoring developers. I have over ten years of experience in agile software development and continuing to learn the ever-changing landscape of programming is my passion.

# CONTACT

Email: matthew.callahan@outlook.com

Phone: 480-389-4207

Homepage: mfcallahan.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/mfcallahan1

**GitHub:** github.com/mfcallahan

**Blog:** mfcallahan.blog

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

Microsoft Technology Associate: Developer

# **KEY SKILLS**

#### Languages

C#, JavaScript, TypeScript, Python

#### **Frameworks**

.NET, Node.js, Angular, Vue.js, React, ArcGIS

#### **Testing**

NUnit, Jasmine, Mocha, Selenium

#### **Dev Tools**

Azure, Git, GitHub Actions, Jenkins, Splunk, SQL Server

resume ver 2022.06.1